<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Vouch — Hardware-Backed Developer Credentials</title><link>https://vouch.sh/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Vouch — Hardware-Backed Developer Credentials</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vouch.sh/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Your Startup Doesn't Need IAM Users</title><link>https://vouch.sh/blog/your-startup-doesnt-need-iam-users/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vouch.sh/blog/your-startup-doesnt-need-iam-users/</guid><description>&lt;p>You just created an AWS account. You followed the tutorial. You created an IAM user, generated access keys, pasted them into &lt;code>~/.aws/credentials&lt;/code>, and ran &lt;code>aws s3 ls&lt;/code>. It worked. You moved on to building your product.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Six months later, you have five engineers, fifteen IAM users (some of which you forgot you created), access keys that have never been rotated, and credentials scattered across laptops, CI/CD pipelines, and Slack messages. You know this is bad, but fixing it feels like a yak shave.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Solving the CodeCommit Credential Problem</title><link>https://vouch.sh/blog/solving-codecommit-credentials/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vouch.sh/blog/solving-codecommit-credentials/</guid><description>&lt;p>AWS CodeCommit is a fully managed Git hosting service that integrates natively with IAM, CloudTrail, and other AWS services. It scales automatically, requires no infrastructure management, and is included in the AWS Free Tier. On paper, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid choice for teams already invested in AWS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In practice, most startups use GitHub instead. The reason is not features or reliability &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>credentials&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-three-credential-paths-and-why-they-all-hurt">The three credential paths (and why they all hurt)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>AWS offers three ways to authenticate to CodeCommit. Each one has significant friction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making AWS CodeArtifact Work for Every Package Manager</title><link>https://vouch.sh/blog/making-codeartifact-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vouch.sh/blog/making-codeartifact-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>AWS CodeArtifact is a managed package repository that supports npm, pip, Maven, Cargo, NuGet, and more. It integrates with IAM for access control and stores packages in your own AWS account. For teams that need private packages without running Artifactory or Nexus, it&amp;rsquo;s an attractive option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the developer experience has a problem: &lt;strong>token rotation&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-token-problem">The token problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>CodeArtifact uses authorization tokens that expire after 12 hours by default. To get a token, you run:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hardware-Backed Credentials for Amazon Bedrock</title><link>https://vouch.sh/blog/hardware-backed-bedrock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vouch.sh/blog/hardware-backed-bedrock/</guid><description>&lt;p>Amazon Bedrock gives developers access to foundation models from Anthropic, Meta, Mistral, and others through a standard AWS API. Unlike hosted model APIs that use API keys, Bedrock uses AWS SigV4 authentication &amp;ndash; the same credential mechanism as S3, DynamoDB, and every other AWS service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a significant security advantage. But most teams undermine it by sharing AWS credentials across developers, making it impossible to attribute model usage to individual people.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Workspace to AWS in 5 Minutes</title><link>https://vouch.sh/blog/google-workspace-to-aws/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vouch.sh/blog/google-workspace-to-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p>Your startup runs on Google Workspace. Email, calendar, docs, drive &amp;ndash; all tied to &lt;code>@yourcompany.com&lt;/code> accounts. When someone joins, they get a Google Workspace account. When someone leaves, it gets deactivated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your startup also uses AWS. And here&amp;rsquo;s where it gets messy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AWS doesn&amp;rsquo;t know about your Google Workspace domain. It has its own identity system (IAM) with its own users, its own credentials, and its own lifecycle. So now you&amp;rsquo;re managing two identity systems: Google Workspace for productivity tools, and IAM for infrastructure. Onboarding means creating accounts in both. Offboarding means remembering to deactivate accounts in both. Credentials leak in the gap between them.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>